Okay, and assuming that we're doing an inter-user experiment.
假设我们在开展一项用户间实验
That is, there are different users in the different groups.
也就是为实验的两组分配不同的用户
Is there anything else we need to decide about our population?
在确定总体时 我需要注意别的什么问题？
>> Well, you have to decide who you're targeting in your users.
你得确定如何定位用户
So, for example, there's some easy divisions of your user space.
例如 你可以根据某些现成条件对用户空间中的用户进行分组
For example, what browser they're on what geo location they come from,
比如用户使用的浏览器 用户所处的地理区域
what country, what language they're using.
用户来自哪个国家或地区 使用什么语言
And depending on your website you may have more information.
根据你的网站 你还可能掌握了其他一些信息
If they're logged in with a user ID,
如果用户使用用户 ID 登录
you may know how long they've been using your website.
那么你就能了解他们已使用你的网站多长时间
And then finally you may even have, depending on what you're doing,
根据你的业务
even demographic information, such as their age, that you could use to target
你甚至还可能了解到用户的人口统计信息 例如年龄
a very specific population of, of your user space.
你可以用这些信息来定位用户空间中的某个特定总体
>> Okay and would you typically make that decision in advance?
你通常会提前做好这些决策吗？
>> Well there are a couple of reasons why you might make that decision
出于多种原因
in advance.
我们最好能提前做好这些决策
So you may want to restrict who sees your experiment for
你可能出于很多原因而限制参与到实验中来的
a variety of different reasons.
用户数量
So for example, if you're running a feature and you're not sure if you're
例如你要测试某个你不确定最后是否会上线的功能
going to release it and it's a pretty high profile launch,
这个测试发布的风险较高
you might want to restrict how many of your users have actually seen it.
那么你就会希望限制实际看到这一功能的用户数量
So you don't get any, you know, press coverage or blog coverage.
从而这一功能不会在新闻媒体或者博客上被大肆宣扬
You might also not want to go through the trouble of testing your feature if
在推出新 UI 时
you have a new UI.
你可能也不想费时费力地去测试各种功能
If you want to release it internationally,
如果你准备向多国发布
you might have to go through much more of a testing process with, you know,
那么除了测试过程之外 你还得考虑很多问题
is this language right?
语言对不对？
Is this you know, the way we want to say it in Japanese or something like that?
是要用日语吗？诸如此类的问题
So you might want to restrict by language.
所以你可以根据语言来限制用户数量
Or even you might not be sure that your feature works on old browsers, and
或者你可能不确定新功能是否兼容旧式浏览器
you might want to just restrict it to say modern browsers.
那么你可以使用现代浏览器这一条件来限制用户数量
So, there's a variety of different reasons.
所以说原因很多
And the last one might be that,
最后
if you're running a couple of different experiments at your company at
如果你要同时在公司中开展多个不同实验
the same time, you might not want to overlap, right?
那么你肯定不想让用户重叠 对吧？
You might want to have, you know, oh, I'm just going to take this section of
你可能会跟同事说 我就只使用这部分的流量
traffic, and you guys can run that other experiment in Korean, and it'll be fine.
你们可以用韩语用户的流量开展其他实验 这都是没有问题的
So, there's a bunch of reasons.
所以说原因有很多
And then the last reason is sort of more numeric, which is you may not
最后一个原因跟数字的关系比较大
want to dilute the effect of your experiment across a global population.
你应该不会想要让全局总体稀释你的实验效果
So if you're analyzing an experiment for the first time, and it only affects
在你第一次分析某个实验时 如果实验只涉及英语用户
English, you may want to actually do your analysis specific on English, and
那么你可能希望仅针对英语用户产生的流量进行分析
be able to ignore the rest of the population.
而忽略总体中的其他部分
>> That makes sense,
有道理
and would you ever not want to target the experiment in advance?
你不会提前对实验进行定位 是吗？
>> Well, sometimes you can't necessarily ID
你有时候无法识别特定功能
who a particular feature is going to affect.
将影响哪些用户
Like if you look for all search queries that bring up images.
例如在分析返回图片的所有搜索查询时
You may not really know exactly which space that's going to be.
你可能无法确定你的用户空间
You may also be in a situation where you want to test the effect
在某些情况下 你可能考虑对全局总体进行测试
across your global population, because you're not sure if it really works.
因为你不确定新功能到底是否有效
You know, you may not be sure your targeting is exact, the way you want.
你不确定你的定位是否准确 是否会如你所想
And then finally you may just not care that much because it
或者因为新功能会对流量的 90% 产生影响
could be a feature that effects 90% of your traffic.
从而你觉得定位无关紧要
And it's just not worth the trouble to try to target the experiment.
没有必要费时费力地尝试对实验进行定位
>> So what's involved in this?
这包含哪些内容？
Is this the same as in lesson three,
是不是像第三课中一样
just compute my metrics on the segments I care about?
仅根据我关注的部分来计算指标？
>> Well, you probably want to talk to your engineering team first, or
首先你可能要与设计团队沟通
whoever implemented the feature.
或者与负责实施相应功能的人员沟通
So that you can really tell are we sure that this is not going to trigger for
从而你能够掌握一些确定信息
this particular browser.
例如 这个功能是不是肯定不兼容某个特定浏览器？
It's, you know, is our targeting exactly right?
定位是否准确？
And are we actually concerned about potential interactions so
是否应该考虑潜在互动
we might want to run a global experiment.
以便开展一项全局实验？
The second thing is, you know, you always want to make sure that you have
第二点是 你得确保为实验的定位流量和未定位流量
the same filters on the targeted and untargeted parts of your experiment.
设置相同的过滤器
So you don't want to do accidentally include
你得避免意外地仅将登录用户
only logged-in users on the targeted bit.
分到定位组中
And then when you go to compare it to your global population you realize that
以免在对比全局总体时才意识到
there's something completely wrong.
有些东西完全搞错了
So you want to make sure that everything's lined up.
你得确保一切都搞清楚了
And finally, before you launch a big change,
最后 在发布重大更改时
you may actually want to go back and run a global experiment and make sure that
你可能要回头开展一项全局实验
you don't have any unintentional effects on the traffic you weren't targeting.
以确保相关更改不会对未在实验中定位的流量产生意外影响
because that can be a real issue.
这可是个大问题